# Dilen Govin

602 733 0834 | dilengovin@gmail.com | www.dilengovin.com

## Summary

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in business applications and software development seeking my next role with a tech company to deploy software solutions and make an impact on technology. In previous roles, I automated complex business processes, deployed performant web solutions, and maintained complex codebases to improving operational efficiency.

#### Experience

#### Software Engineer

Jun 2020 - Dec 2022

Phoenix, AZ

Honeywell International

- Acted as the primary software engineer working on the Building Technology Systems Team resolving technical issues and optimizing operations utilizing Python and JavaScript
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop and deploy ServiceNow solutions that meet business requirements and improve operational efficiency
- Rebuilt the team's existing order fulfillment tracking software slashing downtime by 35%
- Developed custom workflows via Python and JavaScript to automate business processes
- Refactored various JavaScript libraries improving API runtime by 10%
- Removed over 100,000 vulnerabilities increasing overall platform security by 25%
- Automated scheduled maintenance for 5005 servers by leveraging Catchpoint API
- Conducted thorough analysis of Honeywell's CORP IT Infrastructure to identify technical debt, successfully addressing over 2000 flagged items
- Configured ServiceNow Agent Intelligence creating a model to classify IT help desk incidents with 96% accuracy
- Formatted location data for IBM Watson model training using NumPy and Pandas

Software Engineer

Aug 2018 – May 2020

Tucson, AZ

- University of Arizona

   Implemented user requested features via .NET and Angular to web and mobile platforms of college advisor management platform to full customer satisfaction
  - Maintained a suit of unit test using xUnit to cover 75% of the codebase
  - Resolved critical bugs and issues, ensuring end user satisfaction and smooth application operation
  - Refactored 60% of the existing Bootstrap front-end to Angular

#### Software Engineer (Intern)

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Bloomington, IL

- Created an internal REXX tool allowing FTP between mainframes and application servers
- Developed an Alexa StateFarm claims assistant for Summer Hackathon via Alexa SDK in Python

#### Projects

StateFarm

# dilengovin.com | Python, Flask, Git

May 2020 – Present

- Personal portfolio website to host resume and projects built using Flask and Python
- Hosted with continuous integration and deployment on Heroku and Git

## HardWare-C (HWC) | Python, C, Git, Tkinter

May 2019 - May 2020

- Collaborated with a team of graduate students and faculty on the design of Hardware-C, a C language based hardware specification language for teaching clocked logic for Honors Thesis
- Developed a Python GUI for simulating compiled HWC code into a visual circuit representation
- Contributed 5K+ lines of code to existing HWC compiler, allowing cascading logic gate sequences to be compiled

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks: Java, Python, SQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, React, C#, .NET, Node

Technologies: Git, Docker, ServiceNow, Heroku, CRM platforms, Salesforce

Libraries: pandas, NumPy, xUnit, TKinter, Flask

### **EDUCATION**

University of Arizona
BS Computer Science
Tucson, AZ